Chapter 1: The Part of the Brain That Judges What’s Insane or Not Is Burnt to a Crisp

The battle with Mr. Hine was over. When Lastiara came to, Mr. Hine had sensed he was on the back foot and escaped. Thanks to that, I was now back on my feet. However, the sheer fatigue and a nasty headache had me tottering, and I was going through a bad case of the shakes to top it off. Had Lastiara taken just a little bit longer to wake up, these legs of mine might have gotten chopped off, and the terror and confusion flooded my brain, which refused to return to my normal modes of thought.

Upon seeing me in such a state, Lastiara shouted, “Sieg! Sieg, are you okay?!” She walked over to me even as she held her broken arm. It was bent in a gruesome way.

“I’m okay,” I said, using a hand to stop her from straining herself on my behalf. “Don’t shout about me... I’m more worried about you.”

Judging by the way her arm was dangling, she was more grievously wounded than I was.

“More about me... OWW! Look at that; it’s straight-up broken. Blestspell: Full Cure...” Immediately, her bone fracture was no more. “So, where’d that Hine go?”

“Mr. Hine? I managed to drive him off.”

“You did? Phew... Gotta say, though, like, ugh. The heck was Hine doing?!”

Now that the spot of danger had gone away, Lastiara seemed relieved, though she did vent her anger about having been subjected to that horrendous turn.

“Beats me. Mr. Hine said nothing but shit that flew over my head before running off, so...”

“It flew over your head? So what did he tell you, then?”

“For starters, he wanted us to leave the Dungeon Alliance if he won the duel.”

At that, Lastiara frowned.

“Also, he called you fake.”

“He called me fake? Duh, of course I’m fake. It’s like, c’mon, really? After all this time?!” She scratched her head with her newly restored arm. It wasn’t often she showed her irritation so openly.

“Uhh...hold on; you admit you’re fake?” Clearly, she didn’t take umbrage at the term.

“I told you already. My body was created to be identical to Saint Tiara’s. So of course I’m fake. I don’t deny it.”

But that wasn’t the kind of “fake” Mr. Hine was talking about.

“I don’t think that’s what he meant by ‘fake.’ He didn’t mean it as in your body is artificial. He meant something more like your personality is. Like, your thoughts and feelings.”

“My personality? My thoughts and feelings? Artificial? I mean, I’ve been influenced by the people around me, sure, but so has everyone. I’m me, full stop.”

“Sure, I guess, but...”

In the face of her firm insistence, I couldn’t consider how she acted pure affectation or totally fake. But I also couldn’t ignore Mr. Hine’s words, given how vehement he had been. An anxiety I couldn’t express in words started pooling in the pit of my stomach. I told her the remark from Mr. Hine that had sparked the most anxiety of all in me.

“And to cap things off, he said that at this rate, you would die.”

“I’ll die?” She looked befuddled.

“That’s what he told me, anyway.”

“I’ll die...” Lastiara’s eyes were trained on the ground. “That’s what my Hine said?” she murmured.

Slowly, she raised her gaze and looked my way. All I could do was give a little nod of assent. The dark depths of her eyes deepened. I got the feeling the madness that had quieted down as of late was leaking out again.

“I really have to wonder why, after all this time...” she whispered under her breath, her hand on her brow as she brooded, “even though it’s not long now...though I suppose it is like him...”

She was weirding me out. Normally, nobody would be so calm after being told they’d die, but it was even more than that. To be in such deep thought after being told she would die without being given a reason for it... It was as though she had an inkling of what that reason might be. I drew closer to ask her what it was, but before I could get close enough, she noticed me approaching and fretfully resumed our conversation.

“Ah, whoops, sorry, Sieg. I was just a bit taken aback, that’s all. It’s nothing. It’s all because of that silly Hine going around, saying strange stuff.”

Her face had returned to normal, devoid of discomposure. She wanted me to pretend the brooding hadn’t happened, and I didn’t know what to think. Should I pry into Mr. Hine and Lastiara’s state of affairs? Or should I respect her will and pretend I didn’t see that?

It took me some time to find an answer. Too long, since Lastiara was back to talking, her expression a cheery one.

“Anyways! The real problem is that dummy Hine putting the ends before the means. We need to go back to Whoseyards and have a chat with someone about his rash behavior,” she said as she walked towards the Connection portal.

Apparently, she was giving up on diving any further that day. She wanted to return home to Whoseyards and get some info on today’s odd episode.

“Shall I come with you down to Whoseyards?”

“Nah, that’s okay. It’s an internal issue. And let me apologize. The duels—they were supposed to be entertainment...”

That did little to dispel my worry. “But Lastiara, shouldn’t I be with you in case Mr. Hine attacks again? That’d spell trouble.”

“Nah, that only happened because I let my guard down after seeing one of my own. Normally, I’d trounce him, so it’s okay. You can tell by looking at our stats, can’t you?”

It was true. If it was purely a question of stats, Lastiara beat him hands down. Almost all of her numbers exceeded his, and there was a gap regarding the skills they possessed as well. If they battled without any extenuating circumstances, she would definitely win.

But a moment ago, Lastiara had been defeated precisely because there were extenuating circumstances. If their fight had been one-on-one, Mr. Hine would have shut her down completely with his first move. With the right materials to make Lastiara drop her guard, he could functionally blank her, and that was a fact. My unease was failing to evaporate.

“It’s okay,” she insisted. “I won’t get so careless again. Promise. So just wait for me.”

With that, she stepped through the magic door, and I followed her into our home, where we were met with the sight of our living room, as well as the black-haired girl standing in our kitchen, Maria.

Maria got quite a jolt from our abrupt return, which was only natural, seeing as not even ten minutes had passed since we’d entered the Dungeon.

“Wait, what happened, you two? Aren’t you back too soon?”

Maria stopped washing the dishes and came over to us.

“Oh, I just realized I forgot about something I have to do back where I’m at,” said Lastiara as she neared the window. “I’m hitting Whoseyards today, so you two can hang out while I’m gone. You can, you know, go monster hunting or shopping or something.” She waved goodbye before hastily popping out. “See ya later!”

She didn’t leave us any time to reply. Maria regarded the way Lastiara was acting with suspicion and asked me if something had happened. I could only answer evasively and say it was no big deal. I didn’t want to worry her. In fact, what I really wanted was for her to live her days divorced from rough stuff like Dungeon diving.

Now that the noisy one was gone, the house fell totally quiet.

“Miss Alty called me. What are you planning to do, Master?”

“Alty called you? Did she come here?”

“No. Early in the morning, while I was cooking, she called out to me through the fire of the burner. And now it’s about the scheduled time.”

“That girl’s everywhere. You can go, sure. I’m still diving, after all.” I wasn’t going to go with her to what I assumed was another magic lesson. I’d have nothing to do.

From the look of it, Alty was in contact with Maria through the fire in the kitchen. Once again, it sunk in just how overpowered Alty’s abilities were.

“Okay,” said Maria. “In that case, I’ll take my leave.”

“Yep. See you.”

With Maria stepping out, the house grew yet more silent. All by myself amid that quiet, I sat at the living room table and soothed my mind. The unexpected assault had left me reeling on the inside, so my first order of business was setting that straight. I took a whole lot of deep breaths—which resulted in a peculiar sense of isolation. I’d been left to my own devices for the first time in a while. As of late, I always had someone or other by my side. Right after I was dropped into this world, I was tormented by loneliness, but that crushing solitude had eased off at some point. And while I chastised myself for my selfishness, I also figured it was only human nature to covet what they didn’t have and find what they did have a chore. It made me painfully aware of how immature I was.

Basically, I’m just a kid. A kid who’s got his hands full thinking about himself.

If I were an adult, I’d have an adult’s emotional elbow room, and I’d have no excuse to keep putting off coming to grips with Maria’s feelings of infatuation indefinitely. And to bring up something that just happened, I’d have no excuse not to accompany Lastiara to Whoseyards. There’d be no rift between me and Lastiara, I’d be able to understand Mr. Hine’s desperate pleas, and Dia would never have gotten so grievously hurt...

But all of that was in the past. It was all immutable. Owing to my inexperience, I couldn’t deal with it aptly. I didn’t for a second think I’d made all the most optimal choices. For one, I was regretting not insisting on accompanying Lastiara just now, even if it meant forcing it on her. But at the same time, I had to wonder whether it was my place to probe so deep into her personal life.

You know what? It’s simple. I just don’t have the power or the leeway to assess things properly. And as such, I need to get stronger.

I was determined. Instead of lamenting the past, I’d grow as a person, even if only a little. I passed through Connection and returned to Floor 20. Not that I was planning to explore floors this deep on my own, obviously. It wasn’t that I thought I wasn’t equal to the task, but it couldn’t be denied that the danger factor went up compared to diving as a duo. And more than anything, if I ventured too deep without Lastiara, she’d give me an earful.

Accordingly, I decided to go monster hunting.

I wanted to get stronger. I couldn’t resolve my mental immaturity in a day, but in this world, I could solve my physical weakness in a brief span of time. So of course, I’d start thinking about compensating for my inadequacies by training up my body. It couldn’t hurt to use the time on my hands to level up so that I could make the best decisions—and so I wouldn’t be creating yet more regrets to lament.

The first step was to select a suitable hunting ground. The strongest monsters I could hunt by myself without issue were the Furies on Floor 21. That didn’t, however, make Furies the most efficient monsters for level grinding. They did dispense a lot of EXP, but they also enjoyed high natural bulk. Taking into account the amount of time it required to kill one, I couldn’t say it was the most time-effective enemy.

The ideal monster was one I could kill with a single swing of my sword. In addition, the brevity of the time it took to find the monster and how many of them appeared at a time were important. Lastly, the less that was irregular about the monster, the better.

Through the experience I had cultivated back on Earth playing video games, I racked my brain for the best candidate. Thinking back upon the monsters I’d fought thus far, I concluded that the floor that struck the right balance was Floor 15, so I headed there.

As expected, it proved to be the ideal hunting ground. There, I tore through various monsters without reprieve, amassing more and more EXP and magic gems. I turned off my soul and just killed, killed, killed. Since the enemies died in one sword swing, I didn’t expend much MP to speak of. By leveling up, my max MP went up, which increased the amount of MP I recovered passively. Perhaps that was why I was able to keep hunting semi-permanently.

From time to time, Lastiara’s and Maria’s faces flashed through my mind. So too did the face of Alty, the one who wanted me to grant her wish. Even so, I kept on hacking and slashing. I had to go back to my world. My Great Return. And the best way to make it happen was the hunting that I was doing now. That was what I told myself as I devoted my time to level grinding, my headspace reverting to video game-mode.

I did it all the livelong day, as though what I was actually slicing up were my doubts and apprehension...

◆◆◆◆◆

Having completed my hunt for the day, I returned home. In a day’s time, I’d acquired more EXP than ever before. And needless to say, I’d met the required amount to level up. If Lastiara had been around, I’d have asked her to level me up, but to my chagrin, she wasn’t back yet. I reckoned that since she’d made her way down to Whoseyards, she wouldn’t be able to return that quickly.

Next, I looked for Maria, but she wasn’t home either. Was it taking her that long to learn a new spell?

There’s nobody here but me.

I looked out the window, wondering if I’d gotten home too early. The sun was beginning to set, the red afterglow beautiful. Oddly enough, a weird melancholy impelled me outside. In order to turn the EXP into an actual level up, I made use of my time and headed towards a church, as it made sense to level up as soon as possible. Also, since I’d picked up a wealth of magic gems, I had to convert them into money.

After that, I’ll go shopping for a nice change of pace, and then I’ll round things off by visiting Dia.

The plan coalesced as I walked. I went down the hill and entered the townscape of Vart. Ambling down a main avenue during the nice sunset, I was assailed anew by a strange wave of depression. The road was decorated with magic gems on the edges, and they were twinkling red. Those faint lights stirred my heart, and I picked up my pace as if to run from my own sadness. In time, I reached the church.

Conveniently, when I entered, I saw a priest chanting, and various citizens were offering their prayers. They were already in the middle of the service. I didn’t know if it’d still work if I didn’t start praying from the beginning of the mass, but I sat at one of the pews in the back and prayed by imitation.

It was quiet, peaceful. I did look at my menu from time to time to see if I’d leveled up, only to find that I hadn’t and resumed praying. Compared to Lastiara’s level up spell, the process at a church took way longer. I killed time by checking my stats and looking at the windows. The stained glass of the winged women was so gorgeous as to be gaudy. I used Analyze on it, as an experiment, and was shocked to find it was all made of magic gem material.

While I was looking around the church, examining various things, the priest finished his chanting and bowed. The parishioners who’d been praying also bowed, then got up sporadically and started making for the exit. I remained seated and looked at my menu.

【STATUS】

NAME: AIKAWA KANAMI

HP: 345/372

MP: 221/653-200

CLASS: None

LEVEL 13

STR 7.82

VIT 8.02

DEX 9.35

AGI 12.01

INT 11.73

MAG 29.78

APT 7.00

EXP: 20235/35000

I had leveled up, but how to use my bonus points? Up until now, I’d felt compelled to spend them on HP and MP, but it was high time I considered other options. What was the next most necessary ability after durability and staying power? The firepower to kill monsters, I surmised. And thinking about it in simple terms, STR or MAG were probably connected to that.

【STATUS】

NAME: Aikawa Kanami

HP: 345/372

MP: 221/657-200

CLASS: None

LEVEL 13

STR 7.82

VIT 8.02

DEX 9.35

AGI 12.01

INT 11.73

MAG 30.08

APT 7.00

EXP: 20235/35000

My MAG increased by 0.30, and MP also increased, albeit slightly.

I was hoping for a sudden 1.00-point bump. Whether the other stats also changed in increments of 0.30, I wouldn’t know until I allocated bonus points to them. I figured that next time, I’d try sussing out the rules by tossing a point or two into STR.

After my stats deliberations, I got to my feet, happy that I was stronger now. Then, just as I was about to exit the church, I froze in my tracks. A familiar knight was outside the door. I could sense it with Dimension.

It proved fortunate that I’d been on my guard, pouring power into Dimension, which itself was due to Mr. Hine attacking me that morning. Thanks to that, I was able to notice him before stepping outside.

【STATUS】

NAME: Palinchron Regacy

HP: 311/312

MP: 42/62

CLASS: Knight

LEVEL 22

STR 7.90

VIT 9.87

DEX 11.89

AGI 5.67

INT 7.34

MAG 4.78

APT 1.80

INNATE SKILLS: Observant 1.45

ACQUIRED SKILLS: Swordplay 1.89, Holy Magic 1.23, Martial Arts 1.87, Spellrite 0.54

I delved into my memory and recalled the knight named Palinchron. I’d met him at the slave market. He was the sort of aloof type who liked getting a rise out of folks, so, no one I liked.

I searched the church for a different exit through Dimension, but the door suddenly opened and there the tall “knight” stood.

As before, he didn’t look the part of a knight. His attire was something a merchant would wear and definitely wasn’t easy to move in. The only thing one could point to as being knightlike was the sword at his waist.

Palinchron drew nearer, his dull brown hair swaying as he came over. “Well hello, Sieg, my lad. Fancy meeting you here.”

I knew it was no coincidence. He’d been waiting for me outside the church. He’d entered because I had deployed Dimension over a wide area and searched for a different exit.

“Yeah, what a coincidence. You stalking me or what? Guess knights have loads of time on their hands, huh?”

Up until now, I’d used a more polite register when speaking with the knights, but for whatever reason, I couldn’t be assed to do so with Palinchron.

“Ack, so you knew I was tailing you. Looks like you’ve got yourself a pretty good perception spell too. Your magic energy swelled up all of a sudden, so I got startled and ended up coming inside.”

Did that mean he also had a perception spell? The chances were high that he was packing something similar to Dimension. His waiting for me in ambush and his tailing me must have been thanks to that spell. At a guess, it was linked to that skill of his called Spellrite. It was a category of magic that, in all my intelligence gathering thus far, I’d never heard of.

“So what do you want from me? You wanna duel me too?”

“Whoa now, let’s not get violent here. I just came to have a chat. You drove back Sera, Ragne, and Hine, didn’t you? Which means I’m no match either. I’m neck and neck with old man Hopes for last place, after all,” he said with a shrug.

I wasn’t about to let my guard down. I kept a safe distance away from him and used Analyze on everything about him.

【STEEL SWORD】

Attack Power 2. A steel sword without anything else to it.

He had no equipment or items with which to fight beyond that sword.

Palinchron didn’t fail to notice that I’d raised my guard and was observing his person. He tried to break the tension.

“I’m being serious. I really, truly came to chat with you. This sword, I swiped from some knight lodging. Thing’s shabby.”

“Well, this morning, I was attacked even though the mood in the air was equally friendly, so...”

“Ha ha, I know. Hine, right? I came to check up on you because I know all about it.”

A smirking Palinchron took a seat at the edge of a pew. There were few people around at this point. The priest had slunk back inside. It felt unnatural, just the two of us in the church.

“If you know, then I shouldn’t have to tell you that my faith in knights has taken a nosedive. I don’t want you within sword range of me.”

“Fine, I’ll stay back. I promise. So would you talk to me?”

Palinchron put his sword on the floor, but his willingness to acquiesce only made me more dubious. There were other ways to battle besides swords. Still, it would have been untoward of me to refuse to talk to him after all that. Besides, I had questions for the Whoseyards people, my encounter with Mr. Hine among them. Left with no other choice, I sat at the opposite end of the pew.

“If it’s just a chat, then I don’t mind.”

“Much obliged. If I wasn’t able to even talk to you, I’d be in a bind, so that’s a relief. Tell me, how’s it going? Did you beat all of the Seven Celestial Knights besides me?”

Can’t say I saw that question coming. “No, not all of them. The ones I beat are...Ms. Radiant, Mr. Hopes, Raggie, and Mr. Hine. So four of them,” I said, seeing no reason to lie. This was information he could find out for himself if he was so inclined.

“Uh-huh, all right, gotcha,” he answered, in no way aggrieved that his colleagues had lost their duels.

“Let me ask you a question. Do you know why Mr. Hine did what he did?”

“Yep,” he replied instantly. “I sure do.”

I wasn’t expecting him to give it to me straight, so I was a tad taken aback.

“Don’t be so shocked,” he said, smiling. “You answered me honestly, so I answered in kind.”

“Just tell me already.”

“Sure thing, champ. I’ll keep it concise. It’s because, well—I wound him up. Over the past few days, I’ve been laying it on thick, saying stuff like ‘jolly gee whillikers, looks like our fair lady has been having so much fun with Siegy. She’s smiling and laughing like an ordinary girl!’ and ‘To think she’s gonna vanish after being taken for a ride since birth, without ever being able to lay hold of the smallest happiness... I mean, it may be for the sake of the nation, but I feel sorry for her,’ et cetera et cetera. And it worked like a charm, ’cause boy, he got frantic. And then, just like that, he went to go save her. Ha ha, mission accomplished.”

He smiled the innocent smile of a kid who had pulled off some prank. The gap between that smile and what he’d just said left me dumbfounded.

Chapter 5: And Then the Hero Reached Floor 10 at Last. The Monster Has Been Waiting for You All This Time.

It’s burning.

It crackled as it burned, like a campfire. The house that we used to live in.

Crowds were beginning to surround the home in twos and threes. I had to take Maria and get out of there, and fast. I had no attachment to the house. I just knew I needed to act swiftly.

But even though that was all I needed to do...the girls standing before me made me hesitate. Maria was staring at us with blank eyes, while Ms. Alty floated right behind her, half of her body having turned to flame. From the looks of them, I couldn’t approach either one lightly. Then again, just standing there wouldn’t solve a thing. I took a step forward.

“I’m back, Maria... Let’s go. For the time being, let’s just get out of here...”

It was a race against time, after all. But her stare remained vacant, and she murmured under her breath, “With this, he’s mine... He’s mine forever... All that’s left is to take Master and...”

Clearly, she didn’t absorb what I’d said. She stared at us intensely as she muttered and was about to take a step forward when Alty stopped her, whispering something or other to her. Then Maria grew placid and cast her eyes down.

I concluded that Alty was the problem and shifted my focus from Maria to her.

“Welcome, Sieg the adventurer,” she replied with a smile. “Starting now, this place—yes, this very space—is the tenth floor. The floor of Alty, Thief of Fire’s Essence. Forgive the hasty construction and my being on a work trip, so to speak, but I don’t mind if you think of this hilltop as the tenth floor. Now then, while it’s a little belated, I think it’s time I had you take on the Decimal Trial.”

She bowed in an exaggerated fashion as she spoke, which reminded me of another Guardian. It was the same smile, the same attitude, as that intransigent and self-centered Tida.

“Alty. Were you...were you the one who did it?”

“That’s right. I incited Maria, pulled her in, and had her create conditions that are advantageous for me.”

The moment she said that, I was assailed by the sensation of the world flipping upside down. Deep down, part of me had begun to trust the entity known as Alty. That was why I was more shocked than I might’ve anticipated by her betrayal.

I shouted as I drew the treasured sword Dia gave me from my inventory. “You can’t be serious! Why, Alty?! You’re a monster, sure, but still! We were able to talk things out! I thought we’d come to an understanding! Are you saying you’re just another Tida?!”

Alty drew closer as I yelled. “Yep, I’m the same as Tida. But can you afford to approach me so recklessly, I wonder?” she asked, pointing behind me.

I looked in the direction she had indicated, but I was no fool. Taking my eyes off the enemy was out of the question. Thanks to the special qualities of my magic, checking my back was a free action. And the ghastly spectacle occurring behind me made my breath catch.

“Apostle Sith. You’re a bit of a third wheel!” said Palinchron as he slashed Dia along his torso from above.

Dia’s blood sprayed out, and Lastiara’s and Ms. Radiant’s clothes were instantly dyed red. My best guess was that he tried to fire a spell upon seeing Alty bare her proverbial fangs, and Palinchron had cut him down while he was defenseless. He’d been standing in the wrong spot, and worse yet, he’d been in poor company. Among us, only Dia didn’t know Palinchron. He didn’t know Palinchron’s chaos-loving disposition and hadn’t been on guard around him. Hence, this outcome.

Palinchron tried to reap Dia’s head on the backswing, but Mr. Hine was close enough to block him with his own blade. Ms. Radiant realized that the situation had been turned on its head and instantly leaped away, Dia and Lastiara on her back.

I was relieved that the worst-case scenario had been averted. However, since Mr. Hine had been forced to wedge himself into the fight without assuming a proper stance first, the force of the blow made him lose his balance. Palinchron mercilessly took the opportunity to slash him across the abdomen.

It was only then that I reached them, taking up position between Palinchron and Mr. Hine as I assumed my battle stance.

“Palinchron! You bastard!”

He chuckled. “Heh heh, I’m not your opponent, laddie. Didn’t you hear? You’re gonna be taking that Guardian’s test starting now. I’ll be having a spot of fun with milady and the others.”

“You’re with me, Sieg. Flame Arrow.”

Alty shot an arrow of fire my way. I wrenched my body aside, glanced over, and found her and Maria staring fixedly at me, madness filling them to the bones.

“Urgh!”

Quickly and calmly, I analyzed the situation. My obvious enemies were Alty and Palinchron. Chances were high that Maria had been manipulated into opposing me as well. My team numbered five in total, but most of them were extremely fatigued or gravely injured.

Dia was bleeding profusely, and his consciousness was beginning to ebb. Lastiara was mustering her remaining strength and casting a healing spell, but the magic light was feeble and the results were none too good. She had precious little MP left due to the effects of the ritual and was in terrible condition, unable to adequately move.

Mr. Hine was also unable to keep on fighting. He was, without a doubt, the one who had already fought the most that day. Although the laceration that Palinchron had given him seemed shallow, his overtaxed body was reaching its limit. Ms. Radiant was the only one who wasn’t grievously injured. The cuts I’d given her had since been fully healed. If I lent her a sword from my inventory, she would aid me in battle. But then that would expose the two defenseless people on her back to attack.

Analysis over. I shouted to the rafters, “Ms. Radiant, take those two out of here and run! Lastiara, take care of Dia! Mr. Hine, follow them and protect them! I’ll be fine by myself; just leave it to me!”

If the unthinkable were to happen to Dia and Lastiara here, everything would be ruined. My priority was to get those two far, far away from this havoc.

“Wha?!” shouted Lastiara as she continued to heal Dia. “Sieg, let me fight too— Guh!”

She held her head and staggered. Clearly, she was in no state to fight. To be honest, she would just be in my way. If Palinchron took her hostage, that would turn the tide for the worst.

Mr. Hine pulled a sour expression, running towards Ms. Radiant as he glared at Palinchron. Ms. Radiant’s sharp eyes shot mine a piercing stare before she bowed her head. She must have analyzed the situation in much the same way I had. She let Mr. Hine climb onto her back and broke into a run.

“Sera! Wait, don’t leave Sieg alone! Seraaaaaa!”

But Ms. Radiant didn’t heed Lastiara as she dashed away from the hill, leaving me flanked by our enemies.

Palinchron looked impressed. He addressed Alty like they were old chums. “Speedy judgment call. Exceedingly close to the correct play too. I’m going after those four, missy; I trust you’ve got this? Only I can get the Vart soldiers going.”

“Yep, you can go and do that for me.”

“Right, then; I’ll be back.”

True to his word, he sprinted in the direction Ms. Radiant had fled. Alty watched him go, expressionless. I watched him as well.

Now there were only three of us: me, Alty, and Maria. Upon realizing that, Alty snapped her fingers. The flames blazing all around us intensified, spreading and flying here and there and everywhere until the hill was completely engulfed. Surrounded by this much fire, it felt as though I were back on Floor 10 of the Dungeon. Alty wasn’t kidding when she said I could think of this hill as such.

“Now then, what say we get this rolling? Then we can realize my dearest wish...” she muttered, a solemn look on her face.

To start things off, I used Analyze on both of them.

【DECIMAL GUARDIAN】Thief of Fire’s Essence

【STATUS】

NAME: Maria

HP: 107/122

MP: 855/132+723

CLASS: Slave

LEVEL 10

STR 4.48

VIT 4.02

DEX 2.96

AGI 2.37

INT 3.97

MAG 6.89+34.23

APT 1.52

CONDITION: Mind Taint 1.98, Confusion 3.42, Memory Impairment 0.78

INNATE SKILLS: Perception 1.50

ACQUIRED SKILLS: Hunting 0.68, Cooking 1.08, Fire Magic 1.52+2.00

Concurrently, I gathered information on my surroundings as well, confirming that the barrier of fire cut off any escape. If at all possible, I’d have liked to take Maria with me and catch up to Ms. Radiant. But fleeing without defeating the Guardian before me would be tough. Besides, judging by Maria’s menu, she wasn’t going to come quietly.

I glared at my enemy. “Alty, was this what you wanted?”

“Sure is,” she answered, spreading her arms out. “This place is my dearest wish. This is my dearest wish.”

This situation... This wretched dumpster fire is what she’s always wanted?

“So your wish is to kill me, huh? That romance thing was a downright lie, and you’ve been playing me for a fool this whole time!”

“No, the ‘romance thing’ ain’t no lie. Nor have I ever deceived you in any way. If Maria’s love becomes requited, then make no mistake, I will lose my power and vanish. As such, however it may happen, I’m probably gonna be no more before the day is over,” she said, speaking dispassionately of her own death.

I couldn’t conceal my discomposure at that declaration. “Then why?! I don’t get what you’re trying to do or say! What do you want from me?!” Before the human-shaped monster who entreated death, I was beside myself with fury.

“I want you to grant Maria’s wish. To make an unrequited love requited—in the form of a love tragedy.”

“Love tragedy?” I didn’t get what the difference was between an unrequited love and a so-called “love tragedy.”

“Maria’s love is a tragic one. A blighted love. A love that comes with a sad ending. Our eyes can see it coming. I’d like that tragic love to be fulfilled. If it’s not, I’ll never fully die.”

Alty was courteously trying to explain it to me, but I still wasn’t following. I hardly thought it was reason enough to go this far.

“I don’t understand! I don’t understand what you’re saying!”

“I failed to win his heart, so I need to step aside? My prospects are hopeless, so I should give up? Don’t be ridiculous. That’s not how infatuation works. It’s more all-consuming than that. It makes you feel like you’re losing it. If your crush doesn’t reciprocate, there’s no point living. That’s why I want a double suicide. I wanna steal him for myself even if it means killing him. The ends justify the means, and I can’t even think straight. That right there is true love! Tragic love is the truest love!!!” she asserted, casting her cracked love as Truth with a capital T.

Her expression had changed drastically. Her blank look was no more, the passion inside her writ large over her face. Her sheer zeal made me take a step back.

“Maria has what it takes to realize the love tragedy,” she continued. “More than anyone else...”

Her expression grew peaceful as she stroked Maria’s head. I could tell from everything about those caresses that her affection for Maria was real. There could be no doubt—she felt for Maria more than anyone.

“That’s why, Sieg. That’s why right here, you’re gonna become Maria’s. Even if your bond becoming eternal can only happen through a double death, I’m happy with that, and I’ll make it happen...and then, I’ll disappear too. If all three of us die today, that’s fine by me!”

She’d made her intentions more than plain. She planned to make me Maria’s. That was the goal and the trial. That was the purpose behind setting up this arena.

“All this for...for that? You broke Maria’s mind for something so stupid?!”

I didn’t want to dignify it. Not Alty’s objective, not her methods, not the battlefield, none of it. The way I was now, the number one thing I couldn’t abide was something or someone toying with the hearts of others for their own sick purposes. And that was exactly what Alty was trying to do.

“Stupid? Yeah, that’s right! When I was alive, I couldn’t even do a stupid little thing like that! And the regret’s been weighing on me like crazy, okay?! I can tear apart my throat or rip my heart out, and this maddening regret keeps torturing me! Back then, he left me behind, and I couldn’t do anything about it! There’s no doubt in my mind he went someplace I don’t know and led a happy life with some stranger! And I regretted that till my dying day! I regretted it till my dying day, and then even after I died! So I’m gonna make another love requited! Through Maria, my tragic love will be realized!” Alty made the fire blaze brightly, an expression of her inner emotions.

“Don’t drag Maria into your personal bullshit! Solve that shit yourself! You’re telling me that’s any reason to be throwing somebody’s heart into disarray?!”

Whatever feelings lurked inside Alty had nothing to do with Maria. I could hardly allow this nonsense from her, not when she was trying to make Maria act on emotions that weren’t her own.

I looked at Maria. Her blank gaze shifted towards the ground, and she continued to mumble incoherently.

Augh! It’s just like “???”! If there’s one thing I absolutely refuse to allow, it’s tampering with people’s hearts!

“All I did was make Maria true to her own heart. That’s a fact. I simply uncovered her buried desires and the true fire behind her crush. This is her proper form!”

“Yeah, and that’s what making somebody unhinged is! As if everybody could be honest all of the time!”

The discussion was already over. At this rate, it was nothing more than a verbal sparring match. Alty and I were converting the emotions inside us into magic energy and crafting spells even as we gainsaid one another. We both knew that the fight couldn’t be avoided.

I was the one who completed my spell first. I cast it as I thrust my sword. This was the absolute full-power mode that I had been unwilling to use even during my save-Lastiara mission. This spell was winter in the purest sense.

I extended the freezing magic across the whole of the hill, and my dimensional magic stopped where my sword could reach. Two layers of magic circle came into being, and the snow made of magic energy known as tiarlay began precipitating over the blazing hill. A winter world overlaid on top of a world of flame.

“I knew it! I knew it! You’re the same as Tida! You’re just an enemy, Alty! Spellcast: Dimension: Calculash! Spellcast: Wintermension!”

In response, Alty started wrapping Maria in the gentle flames flowing out of her hands. A pillar of fantastical flame shining in a color that was neither red nor yellow nor blue rose up above the pair’s heads. The rising flames scattered into the air, a fiery snow raining down.

“Sieg! You remind me of the past! Of a thousand years ago! That face reminds me of what once was! By taking you down, my tragic love will finally be consummated! Spellcast: Flame Calculash! Spellcast: In Cadeus Blazer!!!”

Red tiarlay joined the white. Alty’s moves mirrored mine; strangely, our respective secret moves were the same type of magic.

I didn’t understand why that would be. It was too exact to be a coincidence, but I didn’t have the leeway to be thinking about that at the moment. Sensing danger in the enemy’s surges of heat, I went on high alert, obstructing the fire magic through Wintermension. But that was pointless against her colossal amounts of magic energy.

Alty whispered to Maria as she clad her body in blazing fire. “Now, wake up, Mar-Mar. Just a little longer and your love will bear fruit. You’ll finally be happy.”

Maria’s downcast gaze slowly rose, and she stared at me. Her eyes were blank. They were even worse than when she had been a slave. These were eyes that were despairing of all things. I glared at the one responsible for tossing her into that abyss, and Alty stared right back at me.

“Here I come, Sieg the Hero. Lament that fact you didn’t choose Maria until your last breath!”

“Fuck you, monster. Rot in regret and disappear by your own damn self!” And with that as my cue, I flew into battle.

The Decimal Trial, the Trial of the Thief of Fire’s Essence, had now begun.

◆◆◆◆◆

As I charged, I ran through battle simulations in my head. I had a singular aim. My sole goal was to slay the monster Alty. I was confident that if I didn’t kill her, I wouldn’t be able to come out of this in one piece. She was prepared to die. She wouldn’t stay her hand until the moment she perished.

Unlike the fight with Mr. Hine, there was no hesitation on my part when it came to killing her. I had no intention of sparing an enemy who was actively trying to die, and that was all the more true when she was seeking a forced double suicide. It did give me a twinge of conscience, but even so, even though it pained me to have to make that choice, I swore to myself that I’d kill her.

As I ran forward, Alty jumped back. Then, she swallowed up the surrounding flames and tried to compress them. That reaction told me that the Thief of Fire’s Essence differed from that of Darkness’s Essence. It seemed that unlike Tida, her strong suit was not close-quarters combat. Seeing her make that move suggested that my odds of winning were high. If they weren’t, I wouldn’t have stayed to face her alone.

I was confident in myself. The confidence I had gained after successfully saving Lastiara gave me some peace of mind. That sense of self-worth had me all worked up that I was going to save Maria while I was at it. Once I killed Alty and brought Maria back to her senses, this mess would end. Luckily, I knew from experience that it was possible to cure Maria of her Confusion by way of my chilling magic.

I tried to close the distance between Alty and me at full speed—

“Master!”

But then Maria swooped down on me with the flame sword in her hand, stopping me in my tracks. Her blade of condensed fire locked with my sword, the residual heat burning my hands even as the fire changed shape in order to hit me.

I distanced myself. “Maria, don’t get in the way! Don’t let them delude you! Those emotions are false! You’re just being controlled by that monster over there!”

“These emotions—false?! There’s no way that’s true! You’re the only liar here, Master!”

Maria was converting her fierce fervor into fire. Flame gushed out from under her feet, and that flame was now transforming into two fiery serpents. They were the Midgard Blaze serpents she’d once shown me in the Dungeon. Back then, creating and controlling just one of them had left her totally worn out, but now she had instantly given form to two of them without so much as an incantation.

“Wha?!”

The snakes twisted and coiled violently, opening their dread jaws.

“Leaving me behind, keeping secrets, telling me nothing but lies!” she shouted, conducting her flame sword like a baton and directing the snakes to attack me.

“Sure, there’s stuff I kept to myself! But I’ve never lied to you!” I yelled back as I moved away from the snakes.

“You did! You hate me, so you lied and tried to abandon me!!!” she replied as she made the serpents of flame run wild.

The heat of their fire was making me sweat. This was not the relatively weak Maria of days past. She had become a skilled enough mage to be capable of dealing me a fatal blow. Under normal circumstances, I’d have preferred to ignore Maria and fight Alty instead. But if I didn’t immobilize her first, I wouldn’t be able to close the distance between me and Alty, who was behind her. Maria was the advance guard and Alty the rear, and they were thoroughly holding to that formation.

“I’d never abandon you, Maria! Never! And I’d never lie either!”

I wanted to end this by persuading her. I wanted to avoid swinging my sword at her if at all possible. That overly optimistic thought had crossed my mind, and the words had come out of their own accord.

“You’re a liar! Your very name’s a lie! Every time you give your name as Siegfried and every time somebody calls you Sieg, part of you treats things like somebody else’s problem! Through your false alias, you keep fooling yourself, never once intending to reveal your true self!”

I dodged a flame snake only for Maria to brandish her sword and leap after me. I managed to block her with my sword, but only barely. She was clearly reading my movements. I was sure she was being told how to fight by her Perception and Hunting skills.

“You’ve got it all wrong! I may be using an alias, but I’ve never thought it’s not my problem—”

“I... I knew it! So it is just an alias!”

The moment I admitted that, Maria’s sword intensified in sheer firepower. Its fire turned from red to blue, its heat increasing to the point that it began melting my sword.

I immediately turned the sword aside and distanced myself again. Then I cursed myself for picking the wrong tack. Her response just now confirmed that she wasn’t conversing rationally. She was just riding her emotions and listing whatever had filled her with suspicion and doubt. It seemed that before that exchange, she hadn’t known for sure I was operating under an alias—she’d just had a hunch. And because I’d confirmed that hunch, her mania had gained yet more steam.

I cooled my overheated head with Freeze. Trying to talk her down while engaged in combat was backfiring. Maria saw no need to hold her tongue. I, meanwhile, had to choose my words carefully in order to calm her down. And since instakill-level spells were shooting across the battlefield, selecting the right words was a Herculean task.

“If your name’s a lie, then so’s your supposed birthplace! The idea you’re from the Fanian countryside is just another lie, isn’t it? For one, there’s no place in Fania that’s more countryside than where I used to live, and yet you’d never heard of the Day of the Blessed Birth! That’s just not a thing that can happen!”

As I continually dodged her rampage, I finished assessing the situation in my head and screwed up my resolve. I gave up on trying to talk her down, aiming instead to knock her out. There was no helping it; I would be forced to get a little rough with her.

“Maria, bear with me, please!”

I sprinted after her, intending to knock her unconscious through hand-to-hand combat. However...

“It’s no use, Sieg,” said Alty unfeelingly from the rear. “Now quit it and listen to more of what Maria has to say.”

The Guardian raised condensed fire over her head and incanted, “Burn, nixfire! At the mercy of the threads of the world serpent. Agni Blaze!”

Chills instantly ran down my spine. I stopped moving closer to Maria and jumped back. Just then, something went through the gap between us. And that something was fire. A thin white streak of flame, remaining in the air like a fiber splitting through space. That thread was extending from the fire Alty was holding above her head, and it was piercing the ground. The area around the point in the ground where the white fire was lodging itself melted like lava, bubbling menacingly. I could scarcely imagine the temperature it boasted. All my gut knew was that if that hit me, my goose was cooked.

The white fire trembled. Through Dimension, I could tell that a section of the ground behind me was transforming into lava. And from that softened, molten portion of earth, the tip of the flame-thread flew at me.

“Grahh!”

I twisted my body to the very limit and barely evaded the attack. I understood now that that white fire was fire made into the shape of a thread. And it had traveled through the ground and attacked me from behind. I’d twisted my body out of the way as best I could, which had thrown me off-balance, and Maria used that chance to attack, giving me no time to breathe.

“You tell nothing but lies, Master! You said you didn’t like Ms. Lastiara! Lies! You went to go save her! You left me behind and went after her! You left me because you don’t like me, and went to the girl you do like!”

She swung her flame sword, which clashed against my blade. I jumped back from the recoil. The ground where I landed grew slushy beneath my feet, and the tip of the white fire came sticking out. I crouched down and managed to dodge it by the skin of my teeth, grimacing at the incessant attacks. I couldn’t withstand the constant aggression coming from both Maria and the flame indefinitely.

As such, I reached out my hand and concentrated all my magic energy into it as I crafted an ice spell. “Spellcast: Blizzardmensioooon!”

The bounds of the spell didn’t go past the palm of my hand. I had extended the magic winter-zone into my palm, thereby hindering the white fire’s movement. Wintermension wouldn’t cut it to stay Alty’s magic, but given Blizzardmension’s sheer density, it might just pass muster. And by concentrating it into a smaller area of effect, its efficacy was maximized.

Unfortunately, the moment I tried to analyze the white fire, I started feeling like my brain was burning. Trying to grasp fire magic whose roots were so intricately woven made my head spin. Most terrifying of all was the deep-seated grudge infused into the spell—the hatred that made it tick. Since it had been constructed using a host of negative emotions, including pent-up resentment, envy, and loathing, it punched a hole in my brain’s processing capability.

Yet, if I failed at this, my hand would melt into nothingness, and I couldn’t have that.

“DROWN IT OUUUUUT!” I roared as I stole away the white fire’s heat. I shifted the magic’s construction off course, and by pouring in multiple times the usual amount of power, I managed to forcibly dissipate the flame.

“Good!”

I figured my chances of winning had risen, and I faced Maria with bright eyes. I was keen to make her fire dissipate too—but then I tripped over my own feet.

“Huh?”

“Heh. I’m surprised you interfered with my fire. You surprise me, Sieg. But just how much magic power did you expend to erase a single one of my spells, hmm?”

Alty smiled, and I hurriedly checked my menu.

【STATUS】

HP: 286/372

MP: 91/657-200

I was astonished. That had taken way too much out of me to be worth it. Erasing the white fire had depleted my MP by around 200 points. That was approximately a third of my total.

Not that I had the time to be standing there shocked. One of Maria’s fire snakes attacked me where I stood. I reached out my hand to disperse it but then stopped myself. If I extinguished this flame, it would further reduce my MP. And if my MP dropped to zero, I’d lose my one means of fighting Alty. I didn’t know yet if physical attacks worked against her. Maybe her body was amorphous like Tida’s, and only ice magic would work against her. If I didn’t leave myself a minimum amount of MP to work with, I’d be hard-pressed to do anything.

With that realization, I could no longer see a path to victory, so I shouted at Maria in another bid to persuade her. I knew it was pointless, but I tried anyway. The sweltering temperatures and my own anxiety were clouding my judgment.

“Maria, would you calm down already?! At this rate I’m gonna die! If that fire hits me, there’s no way I’ll make it out!”

“That’s okay! Even if your limbs get burned off, I’ll take care of you. You don’t need your limbs; you’ll be okay as long as you have me. I’m strong now. And it’s thanks to you, Master. With this power, I can earn us money through the Dungeon. There won’t be an issue! Let’s just live life, the two of us alone in that house!!!”

Maria pointed at the house, which was on the verge of collapsing, and smiled broadly. As I fought on the scorching red battlefield, ice ran down my spine. There was no hope of persuading her. Her smile made that abundantly clear.

Since my words had lost their power, I moved to restrain her using just my physical prowess. But of course, Alty wasn’t about to let me.

“Sprout, birthfire! Universal blestfire of the original sin! Janua Blaze!!!”

A flower of flame bloomed at Maria’s feet. It spread its petals like a lily and came at me. I couldn’t avoid it—I had to distance myself from her.

The flower of flame then wriggled and something red scattered at its center. It fluttered like pollen and fell to the ground, giving rise to yet more flowers. Realizing that it was a wide-range spell, I once again tried to put more distance between us, but my movements were blocked by the wall of flames behind me. Due to the many fire spells in play, I’d lost any way out before I knew it.

The fiery flower garden was proliferating like mad before my eyes. I considered how to break this deadlock, counting all the cards up my sleeve and searching for an effective way forward. But though I thought through various combinations of card plays, none of them proved game-changing.

The gears in my head were turning at hyper speed, but my simulations were all predicting naught but my demise. At the same time, I was attacked by the sensation of something crawling up my back. It was “???” sidling up to me.

I do not accept that. I absolutely refuse to submit to “???”

I continued to rack my brain for a solution, unaided by “???” And then, I found one card up my sleeve that I had yet to use.

“All skill points to Ice Magic!”

A notification box appeared in my field of view.

【ALL SKILL POINTS ALLOTTED TO ICE MAGIC】

Ice Magic 2.06+1.10

I used the eleven skill points I’d never touched. I also released the Connection spell that was applying a -200 to my MP and poured all of the magic power inside me into my ice magic. By using every one of my trump cards, I successfully strengthened the cold of Wintermension. My understanding of ice magic deepened; my grip on the molecular vibration grew.

How can I put a stop to the world’s vibrations? No, how can I glaciate the whole wide world?

And I arrived at one facet of the answer. “Freeze! FREEEEZE!!!”

An unprecedented giant wave of cold grew more and more refined. I clad myself in it like a robe and braced against the oncoming flames. Moreover, I took water and cloth out of my inventory, soaked the cloth, and donned it like a mantle from my head downward before breaking into a dash.

In response to my attempt to run through the field, the fire flowers enlarged their petals so as to catch me. Some touched me.

“Yarrrgh!”

They caught me on the back. The cloth was burned away, scorching my flesh. I didn’t feel the sensation of heat anymore. Nor was there pain. All that blared in my brain was, Warning, warning, warning.

I ignored all that and kept on running, only to be blocked by Maria, who was walking through the flames freely. I couldn’t afford to pay her any heed. I simply endured the flame sword tearing through my shoulder and ran as fast as my legs could carry me past her over to Alty.

“Made it to me, huh, Sieg?!!!” The Guardian smiled at the sight of my desperate charge. The very same smile Tida had once shown me.

“ALTYYYYY!!!” I screamed. It burned my mouth, my throat, my insides, but all the same, I screamed.

“World-shaking flames almighty! Resolve more red than the passion of all creation!” Alty was screaming too. In much the same way, she incanted while igniting it all. Her spell would probably be complete before I could reach her. “Bonfire of spurting blood! The crimson snow flurry is my body! The world that is me is now aflame!!!”

And yet, I had no choice but to press forward. What little remained of my life force was urging me to see that this was the moment of truth. I kept running, fully intending to plunge into the midst of the fire spell she would no doubt be completing in short order.

“Spellcast: Diana Blaze!!!”

The completed spell was an orb not unlike a small sun. The instant it flashed on like a lamp, everything was wrapped in flames. My sense organs lost all their faculties, and I could feel my body burning.

Regardless, I kept going, advancing into the thick of the inferno. I knew that I had no other choice, both to protect my body and for all the other reasons. My limbs lacked all sense of touch, but I forced them to keep moving.

I guarded my face with my left hand and used my right hand to slash Alty’s torso. In that same burst of forward motion, I went past her and kept running. As a result, I took the brunt of the heat blasted by the miniature sun from behind. Concentrating my cold towards my rear, I ran with the intent to flee the onslaught.

Due to the impact and the heat pushing me from behind, I couldn’t even fall safely. I tumbled and rolled like a ball. Although the cloak I had been wearing was burned to ash, it seemed I was able to avoid a fatal blow due to my strengthened ice magic. And I could feel it in my hands—I’d definitely given Alty a nice gash.

I slowly got to my feet and checked to see how she was doing. She was standing, having been slashed diagonally from shoulder to waist. She looked at me and smiled, holding in the blood flowing out of her with her hand. It was on fire. She smiled despite the wound, which would be more than grievous for any human. That smile was enough to tell me that our fight wasn’t over.

In place of the MP I’d run out of, I cast more magic by dipping into my life force.

“Spellcast: Dimension: Calculash...”

【STATUS】

HP: 246/372

MP: 0/657

HP: 238/366

MP: 0/657

I wasn’t there yet. It wasn’t over yet. Recalling the time I had battled Tida, I watched calmly as the measure of my life ticked down.

“I expected no less, Sieg. You do have the mettle it took to kill Tida, after all,” Alty said placidly as she bled burning blood.

“Shut up! Just eat shit and die already!”

I pulled a fresh new dampened mantle from my inventory and put it on, then brandished my sword once more. I had 238 HP left to work with. From a numerical standpoint, I could keep going. It was too early to throw in the towel. I vowed to myself that I would save Maria, just like I’d saved Lastiara.

“But it’s still not enough. You’re still lacking. Isn’t that right, Maria?”

“Yes, that’s right! It’s still not enough!”

Alty staggered closer to Maria and hugged her from behind. Then, the two of them repeated those words. “Not enough...” “From now on...” they said over and over.

I got a bad feeling about that, so I mustered my remaining strength and ran. I had to stop them. My gut was screaming as much.

Propelled by the momentum, my sword stabbed the monster behind Maria right through the face.

The tip of the blade plunged into her face. But I didn’t feel any resistance. Alty’s features warped as her form lost substance. She turned into fire and looked my way, smiling.

Her whole body morphed into flame, and then she became one with the fire that was wreathing Maria. Part of Maria’s fire formed a mouth: “This battle’s just beginning, Sieg. We’ve got a ways to go!”

My body stiffened. The enemy I was intent on slicing to ribbons was no longer there, and I just stood there. I understood that Alty had simply turned into more fire and mixed in with Maria’s.

Does that mean I’m not gonna get anywhere unless I extinguish all of the fire here? Or does that mean that she’s mixed in with Maria’s body, forcing me to kill Maria if I wanna kill her too? Or does it mean something else entirely? I had no idea.

While I was standing there, shocked, Maria came forward, slashing.

“Master, please stand down! If you do, we can start over from square one! From that point in time! This time, we won’t need anyone else! Let’s start over, just the two of us!”

All I could do was keep deflecting her blows, because I didn’t know how to attack Alty. Left with no other choice, I resorted to trying to persuade Maria again.

“Maria! I need you to come back to your senses! Everything about this is just dancing to her tune! There’s no point in fighting me! There are no do-overs in life!”

“Even if that’s true, Ms. Alty was there for me until the end! I was so lonely, and she did her best to help me! Unlike you, she didn’t leave me out, or leave me alone, or leave me behind!”

She merely fired back with more criticism. I got the sense that the more we talked, the stronger her fire grew. There was no doubt about it—there was a close link between Maria’s mentality and her fervor.

I shouted as I strengthened the cold air using Wintermension, “I’ll never leave you alone or leave you behind again! I promise! So please, retract your fire!”

“More lies! If you’re not lying, why did you go save Ms. Lastiara? If she’s around, I’ll never be able to keep up. I’ll get left behind. I’ll be all alone again. How could you go save her when you knew that’d happen?!”

“Nothing will change if she’s around! It’s okay; we’ll all be together! So—”

“Ever since she—ever since Ms. Lastiara came around, it all went wrong! That girl plays dirty. Being born such a dazzling being is cheating. I can’t even tell you how anxious it made me, watching you get sucked into her radiance! As long as she’s there, I’ll wonder when you’ll leave me behind, and when you’ll lie to me! I’ll be constantly uneasy!”

The more she talked, the more her true thoughts were laid bare, and by the same token, the more all my mistaken impressions came into sharp relief. Little by little, the root of Maria’s inner turmoil was turning clearer. I’d figured her infatuation or envy was getting the best of her, but that was slightly off the mark. What Maria was raging against, over and over again, was something else.

She and I were dropping years off our lives screaming at each other. And if I wasn’t wrong, that was precisely why we were finally beginning to understand each other.

“That’s why we’re starting over,” Maria continued. “We’re going back to the time you were limp-wristed and lost. Back then, you clung to me and depended on me, and that made me feel so safe. I was able to think to myself: Now, here’s someone who’ll be by my side! Here’s someone I can find happiness with! So we’re gonna turn back the clock to when she wasn’t with us!”

Maria was telling me that she wanted to scorch everything and be together with a weakened version of me. She was saying that she couldn’t rest easy otherwise. If I wasn’t weaker, she’d always be worried I’d run off someplace...

Ahh, I finally get it. Long story short, Maria’s a ball of fear and apprehension.

After all, I hadn’t told her anything. Not my real name or my actual place of origin, or my goals. Nothing. She was beside herself with worry because she didn’t know the first thing about me. No matter how often I told her everything was fine, no matter how nice I was to her or how much favoritism I showed her, there was no point if I didn’t give her a single piece of the truth. It only had the opposite effect.

What Maria wanted was assurance. She wanted the security of knowing I wasn’t going anywhere.

“I couldn’t do anything but watch as the boy I like drifted away! And try as I might to follow after you, I couldn’t catch up! Well, I don’t want to lose everything again, okay?!!!”

Perhaps now was the time to stare the emotions I’d been fleeing square in the face.

Maria likes me. That’s why she can’t abide Lastiara, who knows my real name, my real place of origin, and my real objective. She’s scared of her, scared that she’s always by my side. Devoid of any guarantees, she’s always on pins and needles, wondering when she’ll be discarded.

In all likelihood, Maria had always been uneasy. She’d always been uneasy to the point of madness. As I uncovered her feelings, I started understanding her more, little by little. Or, to be more honest, I was being told how she felt—by this, the Trial of the Tenth Floor.

“You belong to me, Master! I was the first one to find you! So you’re no one else’s!”

Maria’s fire blazed unto the ends of earth. She burned her whole body, the intensity of her flames exceeding the power of my cold. In the end, even her swordplay outpaced mine, and she deflected my blade to the side.

Rendered defenseless, I was thrust away by a blow to the torso, putting some distance between us and giving Maria time to incant.

“Burn, nixfire!”

That was the verse for obtaining what she wanted, no matter the sacrifice. For some reason, I was able to understand the meaning of that incantation. The feelings she seeded into it reached me. And at the same time, I realized just how much she had tossed onto the pyre of her magic. She’d discarded her body and heart, her memories and emotions, her past and her future, her everything—all for me.

Then I’ll feed my own pyre.

“Spread, nix-ice!” I incanted. Those words spilled out of my mouth as though I’d thought of them myself.

Chapter 6: At the End of the Day of the Blessed Birth

Upon hearing Tida’s name, my body stiffened. But I instantly held my sword at the ready and shouted, “What... What do you mean, the twentieth floor?! Tida’s gone! GONE!”

“Yep, Tida’s gone,” replied Palinchron as he approached. “So I’ll be the stand-in. I’ll do the vigesimal trial for Tida. The true version.” He raised his blood-soaked blade overhead.

No time to think. I stood in front of Maria and retrieved a spare sword from my inventory, intercepting Palinchron’s swing. Our swords crossed, and an ominous, high-pitched noise pierced the air.

My HP and MP were nearing their limits, so the only support spell I was using was Dimension. As a result, our fight wound up being a simple test of swordsmanship. Palinchron’s one-handed swordplay was bizarrely mellow and flexible. As our blades met again, he grabbed me by the arm with his free hand.

With that, his magic power expanded. A frightful energy seeped from the skin I was touching. Instinctively, I dipped into my fast-depleting life points and intensified my dimensional magic for a fleeting moment, probing for the weakest point in Palinchron’s stance and pouring my strength there.

“Get offa me!” I shook him off and thrust him away.

The bastard’s hands were glowing with dim gray light. The chances were high that this frightful magic energy was a mental spell.

“I’ll be damned. Impressive, Kanami. Look at you move, with your body in that state.” He smiled, genuinely surprised.

I was pissed. Everything about how Palinchron carried himself pissed me off. I endured the pain and screamed, “What are you after?! You’ve thrown Whoseyards into chaos; isn’t that good enough?!”

“Oh, that was just for funsies. And so is this. As for what I’m really after, I can’t tell you that. If I did, you’d see my next moves coming.”

While I was furious, Palinchron was quite calm by contrast. His detachedness blasted my irritation to its limit, and I converted more of my HP into magic energy.

【STATUS】

HP: 62/284

MP: 0/657

HP: 52/275

MP: 0/657

My max HP had decreased by nearly 100 points in total. 100 was basically the amount of life points your average pro diver possessed, and my battered body shrieked all the more for it.

“Fuck off with that shit! I couldn’t hold back if I wanted to right now! If you wind up getting killed, that ain’t my problem!”

“Hold back? At this stage in the game? You really are a kind soul. Or maybe you’re too scared to take a life?”

“I’m not too scared! Now that I’ve killed Alty, I won’t hesitate anymore!”

“Keh heh, treating her as human, are we? That’s so you, laddie! You’re whacked in the head!”

I tried breaking into a run with the intention of killing Palinchron. But my legs were stopped by what that asshole pulled out from inside his clothes.

“You know what, though, it’s true that if you get serious, I’ll probably bite it. Tragic as it is, I can’t beat you even with this many advantages going for me. That’s right—I don’t overestimate my own strength. Which is why this comes in handy.”

I’d seen that stone before. I used Analyze on the thing:

【GUARDIAN’S MAGIC GEM】

A crystal of the Guardian Tida’s magic energy.

“Tida’s gem?!”

“Yep. It’s the magic gem of a Guardian, which you so thoughtlessly parted with. To think you’d go straight to Vart and sell it off. Granted, it’s thanks to that that I got my hands on it now.”

Palinchron fiddled with the gem, his lips curling even further. A bead of cold sweat ran down my brow.

“Tida and the little missy both told me that there was no issue affinity-wise, but I was still afraid. Now that I’ve seen what I just saw, I know it for a fact: I can inherit Tida’s will. No—I’m the only one who can!”

He popped the gem into his mouth and gulped it down. That instant, his magic energy... it went wild. The sensation felt like the world was dislodging itself with Palinchron as the cardinal point. Like the very air was spasming.

His eyes were progressively robbed of their vitality. His already lacking human touch became more and more diluted, and the person named Palinchron Regacy transformed into something else. In terms of his outward appearance, nothing had actually changed. Yet all the same, he had been unmistakably altered.

“Ha, ha ha, now, let’S gET tHiS StarTed, heRO...”

I got the sense that his voice and Tida’s overlapped. Palinchron gripped his sword tightly and drew closer. Impelled by fear, I used Analyze.

【STATUS】

NAME: Palinchron Regacy

HP: 501/512

MP: 368/392

CLASS: None

LEVEL 22

STR 15.21

VIT 19.45

DEX 12.12

AGI 18.22

INT 10.11

MAG 13.99

APT 4.89

INNATE SKILLS: Observant 1.46

ACQUIRED SKILLS: Swordplay 1.89, Holy Magic 1.23, Mental Magic 3.89, Martial Arts 1.87, Spellrite 2.54

He was completely different now. All of his stats had doubled, and his magic was an order of magnitude greater. I tried to revise my evaluation of Palinchron and reexamine my suppositions with regard to his battle tactics—but he came swinging at me with agility on par with Tida’s before I could stop to think.

I blocked his oncoming sword with my own, but the impact caused my arm to go numb. Clearly, his muscle strength was not what it had been moments earlier. His no-holds-barred blow also reminded me of my fight against Tida.

“You’re joking!”

I was assailed by regret and frustration. I’d suspected Tida’s gem was an item of importance, but I’d relinquished it anyway. And the prospect of a rematch against him had me shitting bricks.

“Now I’m something of a monster myself!” Palinchron crowed. “Don’t hesitate to kill me, you hear?!”

His every blow was both weighty and fast. And combined with his sword skills, the onslaught was elevated to even greater heights. It had technique to it that Tida had never exhibited, and little by little, it broke through my defenses. If I didn’t do something, I’d lag behind. I was forced to strengthen my magic.

“Dammit! Dimension: Calculash!”

But that was the wrong move. After repeatedly scraping the barrel to craft more magic, my body was on the verge of total collapse. If one were to focus strictly on the numbers, I still had more of my max HP to draw from. One might then conclude that I could use more magic. But my actual physical condition wouldn’t allow it. A stabbing pain hit my brain, and the spell fizzled.

“Khh...urghh, ahhhhh!!!”

I’d shaved away too much of my life force in a short span of time. I lost yet more life, but the magic energy I squeezed out dispersed in vain. After defeating Alty, I couldn’t regain my concentration now that I’d relaxed it once. The intense pain made it abundantly clear that this was not a boundary I could get away with crossing.

I was now open to a fatal blow. Palinchron disarmed me and swept my legs out from under me. Then he straddled me, grabbed my head, and slammed me into the ground, after which that stomach-churning energy from before radiated from his palms.

“Not even you can resist Tida’s magic, can you? Spellcast: Deprived Martyr!”

Palinchron’s magic power penetrated the nooks and crannies of my worn-out brain. The spell was similar to the magic Tida had once used against me. I was convinced that at this rate, my mind would be painted over. There was no time to hesitate!

If my heart’s gonna get tampered with either way, then I’ll go with the option where my consciousness doesn’t die! I’ve got no other choice:

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Stabilizes your mental state in exchange for some of your emotion.

+1.00 to Confusion.

“I’M NOT GOING DOWN!”

I activated it. The skill I swore I wouldn’t even if it killed me. I brushed aside Palinchron’s mind meddling and kicked him as he was concentrating on the spell with all my strength. I broke my promise to myself, but I had to. The idea of getting hit by his magic now was even scarier than dying.

I could sense an assortment of emotions fall by the wayside. All thoughts and all vows faded away, my cooled-down brain watching them fly beyond the horizon. Then I glared at the enemy who had thus forced my hand.

Having been kicked off of me, Palinchron looked astonished. That surprise quickly turned into an expression of delight. “Keh, keh heh, ha ha ha ha ha ha! Goodness, Kanami, you’re too strong!”

“Midgard Blaze!”

A spell from Maria. It seemed she’d been aiming for a window where Palinchron and I were apart. Sadly, the fire snake didn’t carry enough force. The rain played a role in that, but her eye wounds were also a huge factor. Her HP and MP were largely depleted. I wasn’t the only one who’d fought a fierce battle earlier.

The serpent spewed steam as it moved, and Palinchron dodged it with ease. The creature of fire, exposed to the rain, turned to nothing.

“Mr. Kanami, are you okay?!” shouted Maria worriedly from behind. But she didn’t come to me. She understood her role. She seemed composed, perhaps due to having overcome her discord with Alty. Leveraging the experience she’d accumulated in the Dungeon, she calmly stuck to her role as a mage.

“I’m okay! Please keep casting for me!”

If Maria lost her composure, it was curtains for me. We needed this to be two-on-one.

Palinchron watched us as we clung to our last remaining hope. “Looks like I’ve gotta weaken both of you some more. And not just your bodies. Your hearts too!”

He started running. But not at me. He was aiming for Maria. I ran at full speed, gritting my teeth against the excruciating pain, and blocked his way. Yet he continued to ignore me. Instead of engaging me, he tried attacking Maria from a different direction. I gave chase, bleeding as I dashed. Just from taking a step, my whole body screamed. Every cell inside me was ringing the klaxon, shouting at my brain to lose consciousness right then and there.

And with his composure, Palinchron had to know what state my body was in. He knew that he could get me to self-destruct just by making me move. That was why he wasn’t bothering to fight me and gunning for Maria instead.

Concluding that I couldn’t let this drag out, I slashed at him, summoning every last ounce of strength. But he merely laughed at the suicide charge. He’d read it like a book, and he deflected my sword before punching me in the gut with his free hand.

The pain receptors deadened by the endorphins my brain had released now remembered true pain, and my whole body stiffened as if struck by lightning. Palinchron took advantage of that opening to wrap around behind me and pinion me while still holding his sword.

“Urghh... Aghh...”

He strangled me, applying pressure to my carotid artery. That was the category of attack my body most desperately did not want to get hit with.

“End of the line, laddie. Now faint for me.”

My field of vision turned blacker and blacker, my consciousness fading.

As my world grew dim, I could hear Maria cry out, “Mr. Kanami! Midgard Blaze!”

But I couldn’t perceive it properly. I got the vague feeling that something hot passed by me. At the same time, Palinchron stopped strangling me and distanced himself.

Good. Now I can fight some more.

But my fighting spirit bore no fruit. My field of vision was dyed black and it failed to clear up. My cheek hit the muddy ground, and my whole body refused to listen to me.

I heard Maria’s screams in the distance. But my body just would not react.

Can’t...move...

“And that’s over with. Now the little lady’s in my hands too...”

All I could hear was Palinchron’s galling voice.

Feeding on my last scraps of fighting spirit, I lifted my head and strained my eyes. Right then, the sight of Maria fainting by Palinchron’s hand came into view. Palinchron muttered something to the unconscious Maria and slung her over his shoulder before coming over to my collapsed, immobile form and putting a hand over my head.

“Spellcast: Deprived Martyr!”

The repulsive magic energy once again invaded my body. Even just perceiving that was me at my limit.

I... I can still fight...

My heart screamed desperately, but my body didn’t respond. Palinchron’s power was dyeing my brain black, to go with my already blackened field of vision.

I’m falling down a pit of deep darkness...

Then, as my consciousness faded, I heard a voice.

“Guess this marks the end of the Day of the Blessed Birth...and I’m the last man standing. Just as planned, huh?”

It was Palinchron’s voice. It was different from his usual glib tone. Part of him sounded chagrined.

That was the last thing I heard before I fainted. Before I drowned in the darkness.

Thus did the Day of the Blessed Birth—the day where the desires of so many intertwined—draw to a close...with the outworlder named Aikawa Kanami tapping out in the middle of it.

Chapter 7: Running Up the Score

Ahh...

Ahh, I’m thirsty...

My head was fuzzy. It felt like I was trapped in a dream.

The sensation inside the dream was odd. It felt like my body always took a beat to do what I wanted, and my eyes couldn’t focus. Slowly, I slipped away from the dark abyss of slumber because I knew I had to snap back to my senses.

What greeted my eyes was a wooden ceiling. It was dark, though. And due to that darkness, I couldn’t be sure it was, in fact, made of wood.

I looked for a light. I couldn’t get up; in order to check my surroundings, I could only move my head. First, I confirmed that I was lying on a bed. Next to the bed lay a table with a candle and a pitcher. The candle appeared to be the room’s sole light source.

An unfamiliar man was sitting in a chair next to the table. A brawny fellow with countless scars on his face, he looked around forty years old. From his attire, I could tell he was a man of relatively high social standing.

“So you’re awake, Siegfried Vizzita? Allow me to introduce myself. I’m Rayle from Epic Seeker, a guild under the Laoravian government. Due to your sheer strength, I’ve been tasked with attending to you at all times.”

If I recalled correctly, Laoravia was the Dungeon Alliance nation to the southwest. But I’d never heard of either Rayle or Epic Seeker. I had no idea why a complete stranger from a country I had nothing to do with was in front of me.

“You’ve attracted a lot of speculation. Some of it good, some of it bad. Lots of different thoughts. As such, you’re in chains.”

In chains? Panicking, I tried to move, but my body wouldn’t oblige. Weights or the like were attached to my hands and feet.

Little by little, I came to grasp my situation. The more I examined my surroundings, the more I realized this was no time to be so befuddled. My right hand was being drained of blood from a cut on my fingertip. Something like incense was burning in the corner, filling the room with smoke. It didn’t have a strong odor, but one got the feeling it wasn’t okay to breathe in.

My physical condition was clearly out of whack. Not only was my head fuzzy, but my body was also acting up. I repeatedly tried to muster all my might to get up, but my body refused.

“I don’t blame you for being confused, but calm down,” said Rayle after seeing me stir. He picked up the pitcher. “First things first: drink some water. I’ve got some ready for you.”

“I... I don’t need it,” I said hoarsely. There was no telling what was in that water.

“I see. Well, if you can talk, that’s fine by me.”

He put the pitcher back. Given he wasn’t insisting, he may have genuinely offered the water out of the goodness of his heart. I strove to keep a cool head, then recalled my own abilities. I’d up and forgotten my most basic kit. I could of course verify that the water hadn’t been tampered with by using my menu-sight. Then I used Analyze on him.

【STATUS】

NAME: Rayle Thenks

HP: 312/322

MP: 0/0

CLASS: Fighter

LEVEL 21

STR 11.22

VIT 10.19

DEX 6.79

AGI 4.02

INT 6.60

MAG 0

APT 1.09

INNATE SKILLS: None

ACQUIRED SKILLS: Assessment 1.03

He hadn’t lied about his name. Also, his menu told me he was one of this world’s big wheels.

“I’m sorry, Mr. Rayle. Could you please explain the situation to me?” I asked, trying my best to be polite.

“Hrm...you’re awfully fast to return to your senses,” he said, looking impressed. “Not that I’d expect any less from you. First, I’ll tell you where we are. This is a building in the central area of Laoravia. It’s the Headquarters of Epic Seeker. Since the guild works directly for the government, you can think yourself as being in Laoravia’s hands.”

Rayle’s explanation helped me understand my predicament, and I started remembering what had happened before I’d lost consciousness too. I’d rescued Lastiara, returned to Vart, killed Alty, and lost to Palinchron.

But at the moment, there was one thing that trumped them all in importance.

“Thank you very much. I now know where I am. Please tell me, is there another kid who’s also tied up?”

“I’ve heard tell of your comrades. At present, Lastiara Whoseyards, Diablo Sith, and Sera Radiant are on the lam. The girl named Maria is captive at this location.”

Mr. Rayle had said he’d heard about them secondhand. I didn’t know how much he’d been told. Choosing my words carefully, I asked him about my allies. “Is that girl safe?”

“She’s not dead. More importantly—”

The door slammed open.

“Hiya, Rayle. So, ol’ Kanami’s finally up, huh?”

A cheery voice resounded through the room. A voice I’d heard before. One I couldn’t possibly mistake.

Palinchron! Palinchron Regacy!

“Palinchron, you must’ve been monitoring... Well, the boy’s awake, but...” Mr. Rayle looked over his shoulder and glared at him with a pained look.

“Ah, arghh! P-Palinchron! Youuu... YOUUUUU!!!”

In my bid to get up, I mustered enough strength in my limbs that it could’ve torn them off had I not been inhibited. I also tried to cast Blizzardmension by forcibly raking together my disordered magic energy. But of course, I couldn’t get up and I couldn’t formulate any magic. All the same, I strained my body, intent on beating the man in front of me to the ground.

“Don’t fly off the handle, laddie. Look, I brought you some tasty food. Have yourself a bite; you need it.” Palinchron emerged smiling from the shadows, showing me the bread he was holding.

“Fuck you! Fuck you, Palinchron!!!”

I couldn’t stop my rage from gushing out at his flippant attitude. If it hadn’t been for him, everything would have been resolved. If only he hadn’t betrayed us! If only he hadn’t attacked Dia! If only he hadn’t appeared at the end! If he hadn’t, we would all be laughing it up together in Greeard!

That was how bitter I was. Bitter that I’d lost to Palinchron. I converted those feelings into magic cold and made it run wild in order to freeze all of my fetters. And in order to attack the man before my eyes, I unfurled my dimensional magic to the maximum extent. The iron shackles and chains trembled. As they clinked, they tried to negate my power, but I gradually grew more and more capable of sending my energy out, and my body was finally able to move, if only a little bit.

“What?! I put three magic locks and five times the usual restraints on him! There’s no way he could refine any magic energy—or move his body! Wait, hold on! Hold on, both of you!!!”

Sensing the ripples of magic energy I was emitting, Mr. Rayle sprang to his feet and cut in between us.

They were in my way. Not just Mr. Rayle, but also the magic locks and the constraints. I wrenched my body to its limit, refined the cold, and set about breaking both the magic locks and my fetters.

“Rayle, let me handle this. I’ve basically got the hang of my new powers now. Spellcast: Demystifier’s Retuning!”

Before I could break them, Palinchron’s hand touched my head.

“Urgh, not again!”

His energy filled my body, and I could feel my thoughts cooling down rapidly.

“It’s a simple med-spell. All it does is calm you down. Cool your jets, laddie.”

I looked at my menu right away.

【STATUS】

CONDITION: Confusion 9.81, Sedated 0.45

He was telling the truth; the spell was a simple sedative. Judging by my condition menu, I’d simply regained some of my composure. It wasn’t deleterious enough for me to resort to “???” Or at least, I hoped so.

It didn’t mean all my anger was gone. However, if I tried fighting Palinchron in this constrained state, I knew he would take the initiative, giving me no shot of winning. With my newfound presence of mind, I decided I’d better try negotiating instead. Palinchron sensed that that was where I was at and sat in a nearby chair.

“What do you say we get this started? It’s time for your laugh-a-minute cross-examination.”

Mr. Rayle heaved a sigh and nervously withdrew to the back. Palinchron took note of that before continuing.

“Right now, laddie, everyone sees you as a bundle of mysteries. I figured out basically everything about your moves over the past few days through ley lines, so no giving me the runaround, got it? That being said, I didn’t get to learn anything about you beyond the past few days.”

Then he started addressing me like this was some detective drama.

“The boy who goes by Siegfried Vizzita suddenly appeared fourteen days ago, emerging from the Dungeon. And that’s the mystery. You suddenly appeared from the Dungeon. As such, all we know about you and your tendencies, we know from these fourteen days. I checked every ley line in all five nations in the Dungeon Alliance, and there was no record of you entering Alliance territory or the Dungeon itself. You well and truly appeared in the Dungeon.”

It was now clear that Palinchron was trying to unveil my true identity and background—which were, if viewed from a different angle, the cards hidden up my sleeve. As I listened, the gears in my head turned cold but fast.

“The upper reaches of the Alliance suspect Siegfried Vizzita of being the Guardian of Floor 30. The theory goes that somebody reached Floor 30 and, just like with Tida and Alty before you, caused the Guardian to come into existence. They surmised that that new Guardian started strolling into town. They do have two prior precedents, after all. From their perspective, you’d just be example number three.”

“No, I’m human...” I got the feeling nothing good could come of them treating me like a monster.

“No use denying it. For the time being, you’re being handled as a potential monster. Those fetters are proof.”

He pretended to feel for me as he pointed at my fetters, smirking. I didn’t let it get to me; instead, I voiced the excuse I’d calmly come up with.

“I’m a dimension mage. There’s a dimensional spell called Connection. It allows me to enter the Dungeon without leaving any record of doing so. I’m a hundred percent human.”

I chose to divulge the existence of Connection after reviewing which aces I didn’t mind revealing and which I should keep hidden. I’d have liked to have kept Connection up my sleeve too, but you can’t make an omelet without breaking some eggs.

“Doesn’t add up. You only acquired Connection after you met Maria. I corroborated that with the proprietor of that store.”

“So what? I’m telling you that sort of thing is possible with dimensional magic.”

“I see. So you used a spell that’s similar to Connection to enter the Dungeon, did you? All right, then, I’ll bite. What’s that spell’s—”

“I’ve got no obligation to tell you. I’m just telling you that there’re plenty of ways to enter the Dungeon without being recorded.”

All I needed to do was suggest the possibility. If I made it plausible that I could be human, they couldn’t declare me a monster with certainty. That alone was enough.

Palinchron shrugged. “Well, guess you’ve got me there.”

He didn’t seem annoyed. As always, I couldn’t tell what he was after. What were his priorities? They were totally opaque to me. I’d thought he was just some hedonist, but then at times, he’d display some weird hang-up or fixation. Then, if I found myself assuming he was acting in accordance with some logical plan, he’d say it was just for his own jollies. When it came to how difficult it was to negotiate with him, he was top class.

I decided to ask about Maria for starters. I had to seize upon that, if for no other reason than as a lead-in for negotiations.

“Palinchron...how’s Maria?”

“She’s under restraint,” he said.

I’d already expected him to say that. “Let me see her...” I requested as calmly as possible.

Palinchron’s expression changed. He looked earnest but also somewhat amused.

“No can do. You’re both our precious, precious guinea pigs. There’s zero reason to let you two meet.”

“G-Guinea pigs?”

Upon hearing that term, I broke into a cold sweat and grimaced. It was the phrase I had most feared back when I’d first come to this world. When I was Level 1, I’d been so afraid of the possibility of becoming a guinea pig that it had restricted what I could do. To think the term would hit me now that I’d leveled up so much that the danger of it had receded from my mind...

“Yep. She’s the first entity in human history to fuse with a Guardian. Isn’t it obvious she’d get the guinea pig treatment?”

My heart lurched, cracks forming on it and blood spilling from them. It hurt so bad it made me want to shriek.

“Wait, hold on! Wait a second, Palinchron!” I shouted, worried and afraid.

That, I couldn’t accept. I was fine with reaping what I’d sown, but Maria was blameless. She’d done nothing to deserve this. It was all my fault. The onus lay on me for saving her and then abdicating my responsibility to her. As things stood, I’d already forced misfortune on her by taking her in. And now I was, however inadvertently, visiting yet more disaster upon her.

“What?”

“Maria’s just a kid! A frail, weak little girl! She hasn’t done anything wrong! Please let her be! She doesn’t deserve to suffer any more than she already has!”

“Ha ha! A frail, weak little girl? You do realize that thanks to you, laddie, she’s become a monster that not even whole bands of divers could hope to beat? That’s right. Absolutely all of this is thanks to you.”

“Right, it’s my fault! It was all me! So I’m begging you, let her be! I don’t mind if I become your guinea pig! I was lying; I’m NOT just an ordinary human! I’ll tell you! I’ll tell you everything—so please, just spare her!” I screamed, jettisoning all pride. I didn’t have a leg to stand on. Any thought of negotiation disappeared from my mind. All that was left in my brain was the fact that my promise to make Maria happy was funneling down the drain.

“You’re not an ordinary human? Yeah, we kind of know that already. And now you’re saying you’ll become the guinea pig in her stead? Don’t be a moron. You’re both guinea pigs. Why would we refrain from researching either of you?”

That reply stomped me into the bowels of hell. Sheer horror made me feel as if I was nosediving from the clouds above, high, high in the air. It was then that I realized I’d only thought I’d regained my composure.

The moment I had lost to Palinchron, everything had been decided. Maria and I had fallen into his clutches, and now we had no freedom. Nor was there any room for negotiation.

“Ah, ahhhh, aughhh...” I moaned, the remorse overwhelming.

At this rate, Maria was going to become a lab rat. And it was all my fault. This had all started when I’d saved Maria from slavery for my own ends. I’d foolishly offered her my hand, and now she was about to succumb to a fate worse than dying as a slave. I didn’t know much, but one thing I did know was that being a research subject meant she’d have even less dignity than a slave. And who was the one who’d put her in that position? Me. If it hadn’t been for me, nothing like this would have befallen her.

I made everybody around me miserable. If Maria had never touched the Dungeon, Alty wouldn’t have set her sights on her. If Alty hadn’t set her sights on her, then Maria wouldn’t have been taken captive alongside me.

Upon further reflection, Dia was much the same. If he’d never met me, he would never have lost that arm. I’d taken them both into the Dungeon, and they’d both suffered for it.

It was agonizing. I was plenty scared enough for myself. To have dragged other people into this only made that fear so many times worse.

It’s no use. At this rate, I won’t be able to endure it. “???” is gonna trigger on me. I need to look on the bright side. Remember the good things that happened. It’s not over just yet. It’s too soon to despair. I’ve got comrades. Allies. I’ve still got Lastiara. I can proudly say I managed to save her, if no one else. I can say with certainty that I did some good in this world. She’s safe and sound now. And given both her strength and her personality, once she’s back in fighting form and learns of our predicament, she’ll come to rescue us. I know it.

It’s not over!

I quit my moaning, took some deep breaths, and consolidated the information I needed to surmount this situation.

“Hm, not quite there, huh? So you’ve still got some hope left—milady and the rest,” muttered Palinchron expressionlessly, before prodding me with his next words. “Question is, are they coming to your rescue? Neither milady nor the Apostle are gonna recover that quickly, you know.”

I understood right away that he was trying to crush my hopes, so I replied, undaunted, “There’s also Mr. Hine...and Ms. Radiant.”

“Nope, Hine’s dead.”

...

“He... He’s dead?”

But Palinchron left it at that, shifting right to the next thing. “Sera can’t be free to move either. She has milady and the Apostle to guard, after all. Having lost their strongest pawn in Hine, they’ve got no means of rescuing you two,” he said casually.

But none of the rest of what he said entered my brain. “Wait, hold on. Mr. Hine’s dead?”

“Yep. That idiot cashed in his life to let the other three escape. And then he ate it,” Palinchron replied curtly.

I could feel any semblance of composure crumbling. My heart was pounding, and the sweat felt nasty on my skin. I had no reason to believe him. Take my sworn enemy at his word? What kind of nonsense would that be? But my shallow, rapid breathing belied my logic.

“Ha, ha ha, oh really? Him of all people, dead? You want me to believe that?”

By implying that Mr. Hine was too strong to die, I was trying to brush Palinchron’s words aside. This was the Celestial Knight who was in contention for the mightiest of them all. I wanted to believe there was no way he could fall.

“He’s dead, all right. He was already at his limit when he arrived at the cathedral. That’s all there is to it.”

The only time my adversary wasn’t smiling was when he was speaking of Hine’s death.

“You lie. How could I believe such—”

“Hine’s dead, and Pheydelt’s plot is still trucking. That’s the hole they’re in now. They’re on the run. Isn’t it unfair of you to want them to come save you?”

There he was, pointing out how unlikely our rescue was. And he made sure to add that it wasn’t the only piece of bad news.

“If anything, you’re the one who should be swooping in to save them. As the big righteous hero who whisked the princess out of Whoseyards, it’s your responsibility to go bail them out. Otherwise, they’ll fall into Pheydelt’s and his cronies’ hands sooner or later.”

He was right. It wasn’t as though Lastiara and her group were now in the clear just because I’d taken them out of the cathedral. In fact, now that they were on the lam, their troubles were only beginning. If things had gone according to plan, I could have made our life on the run an easy one by making use of Connection. But I wasn’t at their side.

However overpowered Lastiara and Dia were in their own right, I didn’t know if they had any means of handling the waves of people the government would constantly send their way over a long stretch of time. For all I knew, Whoseyards might capture Lastiara and Dia the very next day.

“Can those three bunglers who’re so ignorant about the world really give their Whoseyards pursuers the slip forever? Not a single one of them seems the cunning type.”

Palinchron smiled maliciously and got to his feet. Then, as he spoke, he slowly walked to the dark side of the room.

“I’d love to join the hunt for the jewelculus and the Apostle myself, but now that the hero of legend and the half-Guardian are in our lap, I’ll try not to be too greedy. We’ve got enough material to experiment with.”

I heard a fleshy squishing sound. It gave me the willies.

Palinchron picked up an object in a corner of the room and leisurely brought it back over to me. I couldn’t make it out in the darkness. I could tell the object was round, but nothing else. He took a seat again.

“First things first, why don’t I get some use out of Hine’s body?”

He used the candle to cast light on the round object. It was a human head. The cranium of a good-looking blond man who was sleeping with a peaceful expression. There was no mistaking him—this was the head of Hine Hellvilleshine.

“Ah, arghh, aughh!”

Hair of bright gold hung over his eyes, and his cheeks were covered with a number of scratches. Red blood was dripping from his mouth...and there was nothing below his neck.

The head was that of a fairy tale-handsome prince. And it was the head of a dead man. A head so mercilessly, ruthlessly devoid of life.

“Ha ha. By using the materials we’ve got here, creating a being to surpass Lastiara Whoseyards is no pipe dream. I’ve got no reason to concern myself with milady or the Apostle!”

Palinchron had just referred to Mr. Hine’s head as a “material.” And I was sure that was exactly what Maria and I were to him too. I grimaced when it fully dawned on me in what way he’d be using his guinea pigs. I didn’t need a mirror to be able to tell. My face was no doubt so contorted with terror and grief that it was piteous to behold.

My pool of knowledge was broad but shallow; pointlessly, my imagination went to work. The severed head before my eyes conjured up images of dissection and disassembly. Textbook photos of a frog being cut open, which I had seen when I was younger, bubbled up into mind. I imagined myself in the frog’s place, and a small shriek rose from the back of my throat.

Am I gonna die too? Am I gonna die just like Mr. Hine?

Am I gonna die in a world separated from my sister? Am I gonna die a dog’s death, without a shred of human dignity?

And am I gonna end up dragging the girl who looks just like Hitaki, the girl I swore I’d make happy, down with me?

Am I gonna leave behind Lastiara, Dia, and everybody I tried to protect, dying with my goals unfulfilled?

Am I gonna die?

The human head thrust under my nose tolled as a death knell in my skull.

This is the end. The end. In other words, I’m gonna die.

I’m gonna die.

I’m gonna die.

I’m gonna DIE.

I’m DEA—

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Stabilizes your mental state in exchange for some of your emotion.

+1.00 to Confusion.

My desire not to die tripped “???” And I didn’t have the strength to fight it. It ran away from me.

【STATUS】

CONDITION: Confusion 10.82, Sedated 0.12

My Confusion had hit the double digits—the threshold that my gut had told me to avoid. And a notification I’d never seen before displayed in my field of view:

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Your Confusion has reached 10.00, surpassing ???’s limit.

Commencing Repayment. The Confusion that you accumulated will be converted to your original emotions.

It was all getting “paid back.”

“Wait, huh? Ah, aughh, aghhh...”

Repayment? I couldn’t understand what that meant at first. I was forced to experience it personally before I comprehended it on an intellectual level.

Then, everything broke down. My thoughts, a violent torrent. A panoply of negative emotions whirled tempestuously. Feelings I had felt in the past came roaring back, exactly as I’d felt them then.

The despair of being used as bait for a savage beast hit me like a ton of bricks. The apocalyptic isolation of being alone in this world enveloped me. The anxiety that I might lose my beloved sister surged within me. The humiliation of being toyed with by nefarious means suffused my mind. The stress of the time I had been wrapped up in an outrageous atrocity gnawed at my soul. The icky sensation of one’s own world being forcibly painted over engulfed me. The fear of death roused by facing an entity of tremendous might jammed ice into my spine. Instances of mind pollution caused by mental magic recurred. And my previously buried infatuation for Lastiara was unearthed.

A mass of emotions colossal enough to beckon death was returned to me all at once.

“Ah, ahhh, AHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHH!!!”

A mere “repayment” this was not. It came with interest. The emotions all intertwined, magnifying one another. This wasn’t simple addition. This was multiplication. And the exponentially swollen tumor of horrible feelings filled my heart to bursting.

My spirit rewound all the way back to that first day I had stumbled through the Dungeon, to the moment I was almost eaten by a wolf after being left to rot by fellow human beings. And now all of the negative emotions I’d experienced from that point up until today hammered into that weaker spirit. The storm of my psyche raged far beyond any single person’s maximum tolerance.

“H-Hey, pal. What’s gotten into you all of a sudd—”

“AAAAAGHHHH!!! Make it stop! I can’t take it! I hate it, I hate it, I hate it! Why?! Tell me! Why’s it gotta be this way?! What about me isn’t good enough?! Why did this happen?! WHYYYYY?!!!”

Palinchron was saying something. It sounded faint and distant to my ears. I didn’t have the composure to process any of it.

I... I can’t breathe...

I was gulping down so much air, but it didn’t fill my lungs one micron. It was unrelenting. My diaphragm spasmed. More air escaped me with each convulsion. Lacking oxygen, I panicked and tried to draw breath again, which only made my diaphragm spasm even more. Before long, it went beyond convulsions into outright pain. My whole body writhed in agony.

“Wh-Whoa there, laddie, you telling me Hine’s corpse is that upsetting to you?! Or is it death itself that’s so taboo?!”

His voice felt distant. Worlds away, even. All that time, a worrying amount of sweat cascaded from me, robbing heat from my body, which hadn’t been feeling hot to begin with.

And indeed, my body wasn’t flushed with heat. That much was certain. But for some reason, my brain felt it, and I couldn’t stop sweating. Perhaps my brain misinterpreted the burning murk of my negative emotions as heat. It was like being made to drink boiling oil while taking a shower of skin-peeling ice water.

It was unbearable. It was intolerable. I wanted to faint right that second, but the pain wouldn’t allow me to. I knew that exerting myself would hurt, but I couldn’t endure my body falling to pieces, and I ended up tensing up anyway—I gritted my teeth and twisted my neck as far as it would go. My eyes were literally, not figuratively, threatening to pop out.

The anguish. The agony. The PAIN.

It was so bad, I could die! It’s so bad I’m seriously gonna die!

“Oh, shit! Palinchron! I thought you said you were going to take your time whittling the boy down! I thought he was irreplaceable! At this rate, his heart’s gonna split in two!”

“I KNOW, okay?! Just shut up for a second, Rayle! Tch! Never would have thought I’d end up having to use Tida’s mental magic to heal!”

Ahh, aughh, can people... Can people really come this close to death just from their mental state?

Time after time in media like dramas and comics, I’d seen characters fall into shock. It looked quite physically harrowing, but I’d thought it was pure fiction. I’d figured mere matters of the heart could never cause me this much pain.

Well, I was wrong. I’d only thought that way because I was immature. I didn’t know until I experienced it myself.

It was no exaggeration. It felt like I might stop breathing altogether at any moment. I felt like my heart might break. My consciousness ebbed due to the knives the pain had stuck into me. It hurt so horrifically that it made me want to scratch out my throat. If my carotid artery was severed in the process, so be it. If death would release me from this torment, then as things stood, my hands were ready and willing to reach for my neck.

Ahh, of course. Death. I’ll just die. That’s right. If I die, the pain will end. I can rest again. I can rest...

My hand reached for death—

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Stabilizes your mental state in exchange for some of your emotion.

+1.00 to Confusion.

The hand reaching for my neck froze up.

Ah, huh, wait, what?

The pain is too much. Put me out of my misery.

I can’t take it anymore. So let me die—

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Stabilizes your mental state in exchange for some of your emotion.

+1.00 to Confusion.

No, stop, please, no...

You can activate till the cows come home; it won’t do a thing for me. How do you not realize that?

Even if “???” triggers ten times over, it can’t erase all of the negative emotions I got from the repayment. With the interest added, there’s more to erase than it ever took from me to begin with!

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Stabilizes your mental state in exchange for some of your emotion.

+1.00 to Confusion.

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Stabilizes your mental state in exchange for some of your emotion.

+1.00 to Confusion.

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Stabilizes your mental state in exchange for some of your emotion.

+1.00 to Confusion.

At this rate, I’ll get slapped with another “Repayment,” and the added interest will only make the negative emotions balloon even more. It’s counter-productive. Do you not even understand that much?

Ahh, arghh... Aughhhh! In other words...

In other words, “???” is defective.

I’m gonna get Repayment-ed all over again!

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Stabilizes your mental state in exchange for some of your emotion.

+1.00 to Confusion.

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Stabilizes your mental state in exchange for some of your emotion.

+1.00 to Confusion.

【THE FOLLOWING SKILL HAS BEEN ACTIVATED: ???】

Stabilizes your mental state in exchange for some of your emotion.

+1.00 to Confusion.

It’s no use.

If that massive hurricane of negative emotions gets any larger, I won’t be able to bear it.

I’m toast.

“Spellcast: Deprived Martyr! Spellcast: Demystifier’s Retuning!”

Palinchron’s voice pushed my “???” skill back into its box. And a small—and I did mean small—light shone dimly on the bottom of the sludgy darkness.

“Kanami, buddy! There’s still hope! If you die on us, that’s putting us in a bind!”

The man I loathed the most in all the world was shouting at me not to despair. By spending a vast amount of magic energy, he was crafting a spell to save my crumbling psyche. For the first time, I witnessed Palinchron being less aloof.

“Don’t despair! It’s not over for you yet! Stay awake so you can listen to what I’ve got to say!”

His spell tethered my consciousness to the outside world. The frighteningly strong magic energy streamed into my body. But that wasn’t a bad thing; it was washing away the negative emotions that were eating away at me. I got the sense that through the flow of his magic energy, the pain all throughout my body was abating. My anxiety dissipated, my heart returned to normal, and I stopped sweating profusely.

It gave me the space to start thinking again, albeit only to a small extent.

“Ah, ahhh...” My mind recovered in the nick of time.

“Hff... hfff... The Vigesimal Trial is yet to come. Did I give him a bit too much of a scare?”

I opened my eyes slightly and was greeted by the sight of Palinchron panting hard. He didn’t hide how flustered he was as he wiped the sweat from his brow. Mr. Rayle was likewise perturbed.

“Palinchron...can we execute the plan with the boy in such a state?”

A pause. “We’ve got no choice but to adjust things to go softer on him than we’d planned. Unless we give him all the hope he could want, the lad’s mind might just go necrotic on us.”

I heard the words “execute the plan” and “adjust things,” but I didn’t have the wherewithal to analyze what they were saying. I may have evaded death, but my body wouldn’t budge an inch. It seemed as though it was as utterly worn out as my heart.

The magic energy that had stabilized my mental state was now rushing every which way in order to tamper with it. This energy wasn’t the kind that had kept me alive. It was more unpleasant than that, and therefore much more Palinchron.

“Urgh...”

Even if it spared my life, having my mind tampered with by the guy was hard to accept. I tried fighting it with all my might, but there was no way out of it, and not just because of my restraints. The repeated use of “???” had left both mind and body on the verge of collapse.

Seeing me trying to muster some strength, Palinchron’s expression turned distressed. “Kanami, ol’ chum, please just take it lying down... If you do, I’ll spare little miss Maria. I promise you she’ll be safe.”

Though my mind was at death’s door, I talked back to him. “Ah, agh...like...like I can believe you...”

“I’m no liar. I keep my promises. As I let slip earlier, if you die on us, we’re the ones in a fix, and that’s the honest truth. If you commit suicide by resisting, we’ll be extremely badly off. So I’m telling you that in exchange for you not committing suicide, I’ll spare the little lady.”

Palinchron was speaking not in his usual mocking tone but earnestly instead. It appeared that my “???” skill running wild like that had changed his line of thinking more than I’d anticipated.

“You expect me to believe that?” I replied. “But I...”

He could change his attitude all he wanted—there was no way I’d take him at his word. Yet given my current predicament, I was forced to accede to his sweet talk.

“But I haven’t got a choice.”

I had half a mind to die just to spite him, but now that he’d thrown Maria into the equation, I couldn’t. I had a duty to do whatever was in my power for her. So I used the last of my strength to threaten him.

“L-Listen to me, Palinchron! If you break your promise, I’m gonna kill you! I swear I’m gonna kill you! No matter what! You’re dead!!!”

“The fact that’s the extent of what you’d do to me just proves what a kind soul you are,” he said with a nonchalant expression. “For real, though...”

If anything, he seemed relieved to hear my threats. Then, having lost the last of my strength, I became unable to even keep my eyes open.

“Don’t worry your head so much over her. I made a promise to little miss Alty as well... Granted, she won’t be saved in the way you might prefer.”

My consciousness was fading. I knew that in all likelihood, Palinchron’s mental magic would be invading me down to my very flesh and blood. I’d be affected the same way Lastiara and Mr. Hine had been.

“You’re gonna tinker with my heart, right?” I asked quietly as it all grew hazy.

“You don’t gotta lose sleep over it. I ain’t gonna touch the core of Aikawa Kanami. It’s too precious to me. I’m just gonna nudge you in a bit of a different direction and have you thinking some stuff that’s not strictly true.”

Oh, spare me. “Not strictly true” my ass. It’s because of little misunderstandings that everybody and their mom had to get hurt...

“Am I gonna end up like Mr. Hine?”

“No, your case is a mite different from his. If I had to compare it, it’ll be more in the realm of what I did to Alty or Maria. Only stronger, as I’ll be doing it with the power of the Thief of Darkness’s Essence added on top.”

“Why you—”

I could’ve never imagined he would lay out so many of his misdeeds right then and there. He’d even put his filthy mitts on Alty! I was shocked and incensed. But I didn’t have the strength to fight.

Palinchron’s magic energy, and his energy alone, expanded and flowed into me. “Right then, let’s get started. First up is your skills. They’re too pesky and they’ve got to go.”

The energy permeated my body, and my free will flaked to pieces. Without the permission of the supposed owner of my body, Palinchron’s tentacles of malice clutched my very soul. That power had merged with the power of the Thief of Darkness’s Essence, which made it even stronger than the spells Tida had once cast on me.

It felt like it took forever and only a second at the same time. And then I saw the text on the back of my eyelids.

【??? HAS BEEN SEALED AWAY】

【??? HAS BEEN SEALED AWAY】

I’d wanted to hold fast to consciousness for as long as possible, but now I was at my limit. I could hear a voice, but I couldn’t tell if it was near or far.

“Phew... guess I managed to do something about those dodgy unique skills of his, huh? I figure he really must’ve been despairing, since my magic coursed through him nice and smooth. Gotta say, though, the price I had to pay still smarts.”

The notifications, his voice, they reached my brain, but I was in no state to process what they meant. I was so sleepy, as if I hadn’t slept in days and days...

“Now then, all that’s left is...”

My consciousness fell to the bottom of the sandlands of slumber and was sinking deeper still. Resistance was beyond me. All I could do was check my menu one last time as I sank.

【STATUS】

Confusion: 7.29

Memory Alteration: 2.00

Mind Taint: 2.00

Recognition Inhibitor: 2.00

Sealed: 4.00

Overdoing it much?

Looking at my Condition menu, I was aghast at the pains Palinchron had taken to cage me in.

And with that as my last conscious thought, I relinquished the waking world.

And that was how my fight in this alien world came to an end. My struggle lasted two weeks. I’d managed to get up to Floor 24 of the Dungeon. On the fourteenth day, the Day of the Blessed Birth, I’d lost to the Thief of Darkness’s Essence, my body taken captive by Palinchron Regacy.

In the end, I had used “???” more than ten times, and all the negative emotions it had erased came back with a vengeance. My ally Maria was captured as well, and Lastiara’s and Dia’s fates remained unspecified.

This was how all the proverbial debt I’d accrued had been squared. This was the result of a mere high schooler like me getting lost in another world and fighting his hardest.

I snorted at how pathetic my other world report card was as I fell farther and farther down into darkness.

Augh...what could I have done better, I wonder?

I wasn’t asking anyone in particular. I wasn’t expecting a response. I was just talking to myself.

And yet, I could have sworn I heard a voice reply back from amid the black void:

“____, _____. ______!”

I couldn’t tell whose voice it was. But it felt familiar somehow.

I got the feeling this voice was very important to me...

◆◆◆◆◆

I didn’t know what time it was anymore. Nor did I know where I was.

Within that cavity of total darkness, I looked inward.

Boy, did I mess up.

Where exactly did I go wrong?

I don’t think there were any issues in the battle department. And there shouldn’t have been any issues with my Dungeon diving either.

...

I know where I went wrong...

It was my rapport with other people.

I never opened up to anyone. While I did try to use them to my own ends, I never asked for their help. And that’s because I never felt the need to crawl out of my shell and become vulnerable.

But thanks to that policy, I’d lost my inner calm so many times. I’d gotten it into my head that I was the strongest thing around just because I could see the numbers in people’s menus, and that had steered me wrong. I’d thought I was the only one who could do anything. It never occurred to me to rely on anybody else for anything. I looked down on Maria, naturally, but I also looked down on even Dia and Lastiara as “weaker than me.” I saved them, I helped them, but I never thought I would need saving by them.

And now, I understand.

I should have consulted with someone. I should have been okay with crying on their shoulder. I should have been more real about how I was feeling. The ideal expression of that, I guess, was Mr. Krowe or the manager of the pub. If I’d just confided in an adult who had their head on their shoulders, things would surely have concluded differently. But I only ever truly interacted with other young people brimming with talent and ability, and I took on more than I could chew, which was another underlying cause.

I got the sense that the more talented somebody was, the more they suffered from some emotional defect. I should have looked for somebody more reliable and dependable, even if their abilities were average.

Instead, I’d spent my days never opening up to my comrades, and as a result, I’d let all the debt incurred aggregate to a critical mass on the Day of the Blessed Birth. The moment I started running at a deficit, I could only have saved either Lastiara or Maria on that day. Put simply, I was already in checkmate by that point. I tried to go beyond my limits saving the second of the girls who needed saving, and Palinchron pounced on the opening that that provided.

End of the line. I lose.

............

........................

....................................

But if I’m ever back...

If I get another chance, I won’t make that mistake again. Not on your life.

I’ll open up my heart, believe in people, and tell the truth.

I’ll live my life as Aikawa Kanami.

I won’t hide behind a pretend name like Siegfried Vizzita.

I swear it.

Next time, I won’t walk the wrong path! No way, no how!

Never again! Mark my words!

Mark my words...

But my vow faded into the darkness. And if I did get a second chance, it wasn’t as though I’d remember I made it. Yet all the same, I swore it to myself. I couldn’t bear it otherwise. For the sake of the sister who was waiting for me, the sake of the allies I’d failed to save, and my own sake, I continued swearing oaths to myself in the black abyss.

And so long as I had that vow, the story would not come to an end. The wheel of fate was still turning.

Until I could realize my desire, the sound of that ever-rolling wheel wouldn’t cease. And of course it wouldn’t. I had yet to reach the deepest level. I had yet to reach the truth.

Why did the Dungeon exist? What were the mechanisms underpinning this world? What was the source of my power? What were the memories of the distant past? I didn’t know a single one of those answers. And as such, the story must continue.

Siegfried Vizzita was going to start over as Aikawa Kanami. The setting was changing to Laoravia, and I was going to forget about my own dearest wish, imprisoned in the cage of this trial. Thus would the story press forward.

My Dungeon diving wasn’t over just yet.